mobpuzzler.com 2019-06-05

# Privacy Policy - MobPuzzler

_Date: 21th May 2018_

_Version number: 2.0_

Your privacy is important to us, and so is being transparent about how we collect, use, and share information about you.  
We will NEVER sell your personal data to anyone.

MobPuzzler enables the visitors of its site, mobpuzzler.com, to be in control of their personal data. We also provide controls that allow MobPuzzler users to have control over the privacy of personal data that is captured by our service. This Privacy Policy provides information about how MobPuzzler processes and protects this data.

We never sell personal data and we carry out all processing operations in strict compliance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“ **GDPR** ”) (specifically but not limited to Article 6(1)(b) to (f) and Article 28).

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person; an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier etc. (the “ **Personal Data** ”).

In this policy, "we", "us", “MobPuzzler” and "our" refer to Michael Rigs.

Responsibility for Processing Personal Data

MobPuzzler bears responsibility for lawfully processing your data as carried out on our site.

## What kind of Personal Data is processed and for what purpose?

### Usage Data

When you visit our site we store the name of your internet service provider, the website from which you visited us from, HTTP Refferers, the parts of our site you visit, the date and duration of your visit, and information from the device (device type, operating system, screen resolution, language, country you are located in, and web browser type) you used during your visit, URLs of referring/exit pages, your IP address. We use your IP address and/or country preference in order to approximate your location to provide you with a better service experience. 

We process this usage data to facilitate your access to our services (e.g. to adjust our services to the device you are using), and to recognize and stop any misuse. We also process usage data in an anonymized form for statistical purposes and to improve our site.

We collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

The legal basis for this processing is your consent and our legitimate interests, as monitoring and improving our website and services.

### Cookies

MobPuzzler uses cookies to process information including standard internet log information, user ID of the visitor if he/she is a registered user, details of the visitor’s behavioral patterns upon visiting our site. This is done to provide you with a better experience, ensuring the security of our website and services, marketing purposes and to facilitate the use of certain functions. Cookies are small data files transferred onto computers or devices by sites for record-keeping purposes and to enhance functionality on our site.

To realize our legal interest to control the load on site, ensure site quality and speed,  we may collect anonymized statistical infоrmation collected by Universal Analytics cookies.

Cookies are stored on your individual device and you have full control over their use. You may deactivate or restrict the transmission of cookies by changing the settings of your web browser. Cookies that are already stored may be deleted at any time by appealing to our support team - support@mobpuzzler.com. Should you visit MobPuzzler site with cookies deactivated, you may possibly not be able to use all of the functions on our site to the full extent. You will not be able to opt-out of any cookies or other technologies that are “strictly necessary” for the functioning of our website and services.

### Contact with us 

On our site you have the opportunity to contact us to ask us questions, for example via the contact form or via online-chat, we ask you for your contact information (e.g. name, email address etc.), a summary of the problem you are experiencing, and any other documentation, screenshots or information that would be helpful in resolving the issue. We use this data in connection with answering the queries we receive. 

If you receive emails from us, we may use certain analytics tools, to capture data such as when you open our email or click on any links or banners our email contains. This data helps us to gauge the effectiveness of our communications and marketing campaigns.   

On our site it is also possible to request a personalized demo for discovering all features and possibilities of our service, In that case we ask you for your contact information such as name, email and your company name. We use this data in connection with responding your demo requests. Through the demo you may also share with us your personal information that we may use during the demo and later for the purpose of improving the level of our services and other marketing purposes.

### Information we receive from other sources

We receive information about you and your activities on and off the MobPuzzler from third-party partners, such as advertising and market research partners who provide us with information about your interest in, and engagement with, our Services and online advertisements.

### Access and Disclosure to Third Parties

We use a select number of trusted external service providers for certain technical data analysis, processing and/or storage offerings etc. For example, we use a variety of third-party services to help operate our services, such as hosting our blog and websites, to help us understand the use of our services, such as Google Analytics or Google Tag Manager. We may share your personal data with such service providers subject to obligations consistent with this Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures, and on the condition that the third parties use your private personal data only on our behalf and pursuant to our instructions. 

We may also disclose your data to any member of our group of companies (this means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries) insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes, and on the legal bases, set out in this policy.

We will only pass your data on to third parties without your express consent if we are obliged to do so by statutory law or an instruction by court.

### We want to Communicate with You

We may occasionally send you notification emails about updates to our product, legal documents, offer customer support or marketing emails. Except for cases where we are required to do so by law (e.g. notifying you of a data breach), you shall have the opportunity to unsubscribe from receiving these messages free of charge.

### SPAM protection

Google reCAPTCHA (Google Inc.) analyzes the traffic of this website, potentially containing Users' Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as SPAM.

### Legal bases for processing

We collect and process information about you only where we have legal bases for doing so under applicable EU laws. The legal bases depend on how you use MobPuzzler services. This means we collect and use your information only where:

  * We need it to provide you MobPuzzler, including to operate it, provide customer support and personalized features and to protect the safety and security of our service;
  * It satisfies a legitimate interest (which is not overridden by your data protection interests), such as for research and development, to market and promote MobPuzzler and to protect our legal rights and interests;
  * You give us consent to do so for a specific purpose; or
  * We need to process your data to comply with a legal obligation.

### Your Data, Your Rights

You have a right to be informed of Personal Data processed by MobPuzzler, a right to rectification/correction, erasure and restriction of processing. You also have the right to receive from us a structured, common and machine-readable format of Personal Data you provided to us.

We can only identify you via your email address and we can only adhere to your request and provide information if we have Personal Data about you through you having made contact with us directly and/or you using our site and/or service. We cannot provide, rectify or delete any data that we store on behalf of our users or customers.

You can exercise any of the rights mentioned in this Privacy Policy in your Account and/or by contact with MobPuzzler’s support team: support@mobpuzzler.com. In the event of questions or comments relating to the use of Personal Data you may also contact MobPuzzler’s support team: [support@mobpuzzler.com](mailto:support@mobpuzzler.com).

Where you have provided consent, you may withdraw it at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of the processing that was carried out prior to withdrawing it. Whenever you withdraw consent, you acknowledge and accept that this may have a negative influence on the quality of the MobPuzzler Site and/or Services. You further agree that MobPuzzler shall not be held liable with respect to any loss and/or damage to your Personal Data if you choose to withdraw consent.

In addition, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the data protection authority in your jurisdiction.

### Duration of Processing

We will store your usage data usually for five years or until such time when you withdraw your consent for us to do so.  All other data as specified above will be retained for as long as is necessary for the purpose(s) for which we originally collected it. We may also retain information as required by law.

### Revisions to this Privacy Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most current version of this Privacy Policy will govern our practices for collecting, processing, and disclosing personal data. We will provide notice of any modifications by posting a written notice on our site.

Your use of the site and/or Services following the effective date of any modifications to the Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of the Privacy Policy, as modified. All changes to this Privacy Policy automatically take effect on the sooner of the day you use the site and/or services, or 30 calendar days after they are initially posted on our site. Your use of the site and/or services following the effective date of any modifications to this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of the Privacy Policy, as modified.

**Contact Details:** **  
**Name: Michael Rigs

Contact email address: michael.r@mobpuzzler.com  
  
 **Contact Details of EU Representative:**

Name: Lucas Jenkins

Contact email address: lucas.j@mobpuzzler.com
